It's about love and reality. Faith and delusion.
Good and evil. Success and failure.
Crimes and Misdemeanors is a comedy, drama, crime film directed by Woody Allen.
A renowned ophthalmologist is desperate to cut off an adulterous relationship…which ends up in murder; and a frustrated
documentary filmmaker woos an attractive television producer while making a film about her insufferably self-centered boss.
Cliff Stern, played by Woody Allen.
Judah Rosenthal, played by Martin Landau.
Halley Reed, played by Mia Farrow.
Lester, played by Alan Alda.
Dolores Paley, played by Anjelica Huston.
Wendy Stern, played by Joanna Gleason.
Crimes and Misdemeanors is a 1989 American existential comedy-drama film written and directed by Woody Allen, who stars
alongside Martin Landau, Mia Farrow, Anjelica Huston, Jerry Orbach, Alan Alda, Sam Waterston, and Joanna Gleason.
The film was met with critical acclaim, receiving three Academy Award nominations: Allen, for Best
Director and Best Original Screenplay, and Landau, for Best Actor in a Supporting Role.
Several publications have ranked Crimes and
Misdemeanors as one of Allen's greatest films.
The film explores themes of adultery, new york city,
assassin, professor, brother-in-law.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional.